Guide to the Dept. of Human Service Studies records, 1976-1997.
Dept. of Human Service Studies records, 1976-1997
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Dept. of Human Service Studies records, 1976-1997.
23-24-2894.
New York State College of Human Ecology. Dept. of Human Service Studies.
3.4 Cubic Feet.
Correspondence, reports, pamphlets, minutes, directories, handbooks, newsletters, photographs.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library.
Records of the Department of Human Service Studies, now the Department of Policy Analysis and Management.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
1946 the Dept. of Home Economics Education was established. In 1969 the name was changed to Community Service Education and in 1978 the name was changed again to Human Service Studies. In 1998 the dept. merged with the Dept. of Consumer Economics and Housing to become the Dept. of Policy Analysis and Management.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Five Year Review material and Curriculum Committee minutes; also Department memos and correspondence, faculty meeting minutes, manuals, reports, and budget material.
SUBJECTS
Names:
New York State College of Human Ecology.; Cornell University--Faculty.; New York State College of Home Economics. Dept. of Community Service Education.; New York State College of Home Economics. Dept. of Home Economics Education.; New York State College of Human Ecology. Dept. of Policy Analysis and Management.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Five-Year Review, graduate level
Series II. Committees
Series III. Department Memos and Correspondence
Series IV. Faculty Meeting Minutes
Series V. Department Publications and Reports
Series VI. Photographs and Tape Recording
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Five-Year Review, graduate level, 1976-1981
  - Establishment and review of field (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Faculty attracted to field (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Applications, acceptances, registrations (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Students (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Publications of graduate students (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Faculty (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Curriculum (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Brochures and Handbook (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - External Review (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Site Visit (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Cornell Graduate School and field bulletins (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Three-year review report (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Masters of Professional Studies degree (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Department of HSS courses (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Human Service Studies Seminar (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Graduate students (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Field of HSS orientation for students (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Summary of field faculty interviews, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Recommendations based on external report, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Department Review, 1995 (Box 6)
- Series II. Committees
  - Curriculum Committee, 1985-03-1985-11 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Curriculum Committee, 1985-11-1987-11 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Curriculum Committee, 1987-12-1989-09 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Curriculum Committee, 1989-10-1989-12 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Curriculum Committee, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Curriculum Committee, 1991-01-1991-03 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Curriculum Committee, 1991-05-1991-12 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Curriculum Committee, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Curriculum Committee, 1993-1995 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Area Committee for the Department of Community Service Education, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Ad Hoc Committee, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Business Committee, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Academic Personnel Committee, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Field of HSS Meeting Minutes, 1979-1984 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Human Services Administration Concentration Committee, 1991-1994 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - HSS Governance Committee, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 47)
- Series III. Department Memos and Correspondence
  - Faculty Positions in Community Service Education Dept., 1972-1977 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Memos, correspondence, 1990-1994 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Memos, correspondence, 1986-1989 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Memos, correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Memos, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Memos, 1981-1984 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Memos, 1978-1980 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1989-1994 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1994-1997 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence concerning the transfer of the Independent Living Management Grant from ILR to Human Ecology, 1990-1999 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Ronald House (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Social work correspondence, 1984-1994 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Course Syllabi - HSS 465: Community Decision Making, 1988 (Box 6)
    Fall
- Series IV. Faculty Meeting Minutes
  - Faculty meeting minutes, 1992-02-1993-02 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Faculty meeting minutes, 1991-05-1992-01 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Faculty meeting minutes, 1990-04-1991-03 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Faculty meeting minutes, 1989-02-1990-03 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Faculty meeting minutes, 1988-04-1988-12 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Faculty meeting minutes, 1987-11-1988-03 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Faculty meeting minutes, 1987-01-1987-10 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Faculty meeting minutes, 1985-07-1986-12 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Dept. of Community Service Education - Faculty meeting minutes, 1974-1977 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Dept. of Community Service Education - Faculty meeting minutes, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Dept. of Community Service Education - Faculty meeting minutes, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Dept. of Community Service Education - Faculty meeting minutes, 1979-1980 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Faculty meeting minutes, 1993-1994-09 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Faculty meeting minutes, 1994-10-1996-12 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Series V. Department Publications and Reports
  - Paraprofessionals in Human Services, J. Wright, 1970-03 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - A Survey of Employment in Cortland and Tompkins Counties (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Status of Human Service Professionals in Cortland and Tompkins Counties, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - CSE 340: Analysis of Teaching - Student Manual, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Community Service Education Proposal for Social Work Training for Local Social Services Departments, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Empowering Leadership in Human Services, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Course lists, 1988-1990 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Social work program field instruction manual, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Professional effort charts, 1980-1989 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Research and training projects, 1980-1989 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Faculty in residence, 1980-1989 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Publications, enrollment charts, 1980-1989 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - An Overview, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - An Overview, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - An Overview, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Graduate handbook, 1987-08 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Graduate field Admissions Committee Policy Manual, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Technical report: "A Summary Methodology for Asking Sensitive Questions Among College Undergraduates", 1990-11 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Faculty: "A Biographical Review", 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - New York State Requirements for Teaching Homemaking, Pre-1968 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - HSS Handbook for Student Teachers: Preparing to Teach Home Economics Development by Marion Minot and Jean Cooper, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - HSS Programs for the Meetings for Cooperating Teachers in Home Economics, 1960-1984 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - HSS "Living in America" lecture series, 1977-03 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Brochure
    - Schedule of events
    - Participants registered
  - Final report, Wilson Youth Project: "Pre-service Experiences to Teach Home Economics", 1976 (Box 2, Folder 36-37)
  - Urban Youth Project (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Migrant Labor Program, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Home Economics Education as proposed interdepartmental major, 1980-1989 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Human Service Studies pamphlets on summer institutes, workshops and symposia offered by department, 1980-1989 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Human Service Studies flyer discussing senior honor theses, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Human Service Studies Social Work Program Advising Handbook, 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Human Service Studies Research and training projects, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Graduate Field of Human Service Studies Doctoral Program review, 1991, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Human Service Studies Connections (departmental newsletter), 1992-1995 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Core curriculum of Human Service Studies (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Plans and Hopes: a Summary, 1981-1985 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - External review materials, 1985-04 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Migrant Education in New York State - an Assessment (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Handbook for Student Teachers, 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - College of Human Ecology Master Plan, 1976-1985 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Educational Sector of Community Service Education, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Social Work Program Accreditation, 1974-1981 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Social Work Accreditation Review, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 6-7)
  - Adult and Community Education, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Establishing field of Human Service Studies, 1976-1979 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Gerontology Program, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Human Service Studies Curriculum, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Home Economics Education - Doctoral Review, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Nursing Program Proposal, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Master of Professional Studies Degree - Proposal, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Public Health Program, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Planning Conferences - program priorities, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Chair search, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - College Planning Document, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Human Service Studies Field Review, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - College Field Study Program Review, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Chair of the Dept - identifying a new one, 1981-1991 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Human Service Studies - 5 year plan, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Human Service Studies - Graduate Study, 1985-1989 (Box 6)
  - Nomination of Desmond Tutu as an A.D. White Professor-at-Large, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Course material: Human Services in Contemporary Society (HSS 101)- Andrea Parrot, Instructor (includes Teaching Assistant Manual) (Box 5, Folder 31-33)
  - "Power and Empowerment," Donald Barr - Final Report for the Ford Foundation Grant, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - "Empowerment and Family Support" - Faculty: Josephine Allen, Donald Barr, Moncrieff Cochran, Christian Dean and Jennifer Greene - Ford Foundation Grant, 1988 (Box 5)
  - "So Intermingled With This Earth: A Piscataway Oral History" by Gabrielle Tayac, 1988-03 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Empowerment Project, Phase I: Josephine Allen, Don Barr, Moncrieff Cochran, Christian Dean, Jennifer Greene, 1989-01-1990-12 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - "Empowerment and Family Support," Phase II - Faculty: Josephine Allen, Donald Barr, Moncrieff Cochran, Christian Dean and Jennifer Greene - Ford Foundation Grant, 1990 (Box 5)
  - Human Service Studies Graduate Handbooks, 1976 (Box 3)
  - Human Service Studies Graduate Handbooks, 1977 (Box 3)
  - Human Service Studies Graduate Handbooks, 1980 (Box 3)
  - Human Service Studies Graduate Handbooks, 1982-1983 (Box 3)
  - Human Service Studies Graduate Handbooks, 1985-1987 (Box 3)
  - Human Service Studies Graduate Handbooks, 1989-1998 (Box 3)
  - Human Service Studies Graduate Student Directories, 1985-1995 (Box 3)
  - Evolution of the Department of Human Service Studies (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Annual Reports, Department of Community Service Education, 1972-1973 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Annual Reports, Department of Community Service Education, 1974-1975 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Annual Reports, Department of Community Service Education, 1976-1977 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Annual Reports, Department of Community Service Education, 1977-1978 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Faculty Annual Reports, 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Annual Reports, Human Service Studies Highlights, 1980-1987 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Human Service Studies Highlights, Reports to the Dean, 1988-1995 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Budget Conference material, 1989-1993 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Budget Conference material, 1993-1996 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - The Trellis Vol. II, 1992-05 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - The Trellis Vol. VII Community Learning and Service Partnership (CLASP), 1997-05 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Migrant Report - Elizabeth Reilinger and Candace Widmer, Undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Series VI. Photographs and Tape Recording
  - Photographs, student teaching centers (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Exit Report of Site Visitors, 1981-11-11; tr-9961 (Box 7, Folder 12)